I still remember how shocked I was.
There was no warning at all,
and the reality was so cruel.
The warm hands that used to pat my head…
The kind smile that used to heal my heart…
He was stronger, kinder, and
more diligent than anyone…
And even he couldn't achieve his dreams?
It made no sense.
Of course I felt some guilt.
But still…
[Ayanokoji Kiyotaka]
I couldn't forgive that man.
If it meant taking him down,
I would harden my soft heart,
and work towards my true goal.
What a view!
[An Ominous Opening]
Did you not see it last year?
Well, I did see a little of it,
but was too focused on having fun
with my friends to appreciate it.
It still kinda doesn't feel real.
It's not that often you get to go
on a cruise, after all.
That's not what I meant.
I meant going out with you.
You never pick up on these things.
So, how's it for you?
Does it feel real for you yet?
I'm… not sure.
It both does and doesn't.
The heck does that mean?
Well, I never imagined being able to meet
outside without anybody seeing us.
There is that, I guess.
Depending on the details they
announce for the exam,
I may have to ask you for a favor.
I get that.
And I'll do it if I can.
Looks like the first-years are done.
We can't be seen together,
so I'll head over first.
Why would you sit here?!
Are you doing this on purpose?!
Completely.
Ugh, why should I have to mov…
I will now explain the rules for the
deserted island special exam.
Starting tomorrow, for two weeks, you will
compete for points in a survival exam.
Emptied groups are eliminated,
and the five lowest-scoring
groups will be expelled.
There are two ways to earn points.
The first is basic movement.
The island is split into a 100-cell grid.
Move to specified cells for points.
Four cells will be specified per day,
announced at fixed times.
Rules govern these. Three per day will be
within two cells cardinally
or one cell diagonally from the last.
But, once per day, a cell
will be chosen randomly,
so you can make no predictions.
The first group to arrive will get ten points,
the second five, the third three,
and all who arrive in time will
receive one bonus point.
but a group's arrival time is determined
by when the full group is present.
And if your group happens to already be
in a cell when it is specified,
you will get one point, but not
this Early Bird bonus.
Failure to arrive in three specified
cells in a row will be penalized.
Before I explain the other
method of earning points,
take a look at this.
We will have you wear these watches
until the exam is over,
and distribute linked
tablets to each of you.
These will be essential tools that
determine your point awards.
We will be monitoring
your health at all times,
and if your vitals cross a set line,
a warning alarm will sound.
It is set to stop after five seconds,
but if you remain over
the line, it will repeat.
If this continues,
it will change to an emergency alert.
In this case, you are to undergo a medical
checkup at the starting zone,
but if you cannot reach it,
you will drop out and may be penalized.
If your emergency alert stays
active for five minutes,
the teaching and medical staff will
rush to your GPS location.
Naturally, forcible removal and equipment
malfunctions will disable point gains.
You must exchange your watch for
a new one at the start zone.
Now, let's return to basic movement.
During the exam, groups will not
all be moving to the same areas.
These watches contain
twelve different tables.
Your table will determine all of your
specified cells from start to finish.
Naturally, all members of a group
will be on the same table,
and if you form a large group, you
will all switch to the same table.
The second method of earning points is completing
tasks set around the island.
The tasks' locations and content
cannot be predicted.
You can view their
participation conditions,
but you must make your way
to them to learn their contents.
Completing a task can reward
you with food or water.
Groups will be approved if they
link their watches.
Now, Acting Director Tsukishiro has
his own speech to give you.
Tsukishiro here.
This deserted island exam is of an
unprecedentedly large scale.
I would like to give you all just
one word of warning.
In its role as your guardian here,
the school will maintain
maximum surveillance.
But that does not mean its vision
extends across the entire island.
Sexual troublemakers will be
penalized without hesitation,
and we will report any
crimes to the police.
And one more thing.
There may be some who become frustrated
over a lack of food or water,
causing scuffles with other students.
To a certain extent, I
intend to allow this.
This is because it is impossible
to entirely prevent strife.
Of course, if the line of criminality is
crossed, the school will intervene.
Depending on circumstances,
you may be dropped from the
exam, or even expelled.
That is all.
I ask that you please act as befits Advanced
Nurturing High School students.
[Advanced Nurturing High School Deserted Island
Special Exam] Thank you, Acting Director Tsukishiro.
Now, for our last topic, we will move on
to essential food and tools.
[Deserted Island Survival Set] Now, for our last
topic, we will move on to essential food and tools.
Whoa, look at all that!
Is this really enough for everyone?
Wh-What?!
How to put it? I guess we both
have difficult personalities.
It's not easy to join the rabble.
Huh?! Don't lump me in with you!
I can do it just fine.
What are you doing?
I thought I'd get… all the water… we'd need.
I thought I'd get… all
the water… we'd need.
Potable water is precious,
but it seems I'll have to either find it
on-site or earn it from tasks.
How'd you sleep last night?
Normally.
You're not feeling sick, are you?
Still holding last year against me?
No, just teasing you.
The special exam is starting,
yet you seem rather relaxed.
Panicking won't change anything.
[Time until next area announcement
Time to reach area Target area]
Mine's F9.
Looks like we're on different tables.
I won't be worrying about you anymore.
Just get a high rank, even on your own.
I'd like to,
but it won't be funny if I end up
being the only one expelled.
That would be a problem, yes.
I just lent you some points, after all.
That's your issue?
I can't blame you for being low on funds,
given your contract with Kushida,
but giving up half your points
every month is too much.
I'm all too aware of that.
Don't push yourself too hard. This will
be really hard for a girl on her own.
I'll just take that as
a bit of kind advice.
None of the second-year
groups are in a rush.
The first-years got more than
ten minutes' head start.
Wasting stamina racing for the first
area would be a poor strategy.
Is Koenji seriously aiming to take first?
Beats me. We made a bet, yes,
but I have no idea how
he'll try to handle it.
Promises are non-binding, after all.
Alriiiight! Let's go get number one!
Hurry it up, Nishino! You too, Tsube!
It's too hot. Don't ask the impossible.
Besides, it's too late
to beat the firsties.
When you give up, it's all over!
Who knows! The firsties
might be taking it easy!
Give it a rest! It'd just
be a waste of stamina.
Or, hey, just go it alone.
But then we wouldn't get the Early Bird bonus,
and it'd be a pain to regroup!
There you are!
Need something?
Not in particular.
Just to tell you…
I'm not going to lose. Ever.
Does she even understand how
hard this exam will be?
She seems incredibly motivated, at least.
Having a rival is a good thing.
Not that I view her as one.
If nothing else, I'm relieved
we're on different tables.
And now…
It's time I got going.
One of the points of this exam is to avoid
missing any designated cells.
Early Bird bonuses and high placement in tasks
can get you five or ten points,
but that takes a lot of
skills, smarts, and luck.
As such, getting one point at a time,
every time, will be crucial.
Are you discussing the next area?
Oh, Kiyopon.
Our first area was here, in D8.
We're already done.
Where are you headed, Kiyotaka?
D7, one cell north.
We could have stayed together if only
we were on the same table.
Well, there are twelve.
Anyway, I'm going to get going to my area.
It's a bit sad to part, so I hope we
can find time to chat longer!
There are a lot of ways to
cooperate across groups,
Take care!
- but if they have members that'd hold me back,
but if they have members
that'd hold me back,
I have to avoid them.
I'm lucky we're on
different tables this time.
I should head for the center of the cell,
to be ready to go any direction.
If I want to determine
who else is on my table,
my only option is direct observation.
Good morning.
Nanase. Where are Hosen and Amasawa?
Investigating the area.
I decided to come here to see how
many other groups there are.
The same as me, then.
I expect you'll have your share of
troubles on your own. Take care.
Excuse me.
Three hours until the
next area gets announced.
So it's either wait, or go for a task.
Hey there, Ayanokoji!
So you came here? Too bad, though.
The deadline was five minutes ago.
So it seems.
You don't have to be in such a hurry.
You're allowed to spectate.
I think it's problematic when teachers
try to steal students' time.
Aww, that's a bit harsh, don't you think?
I just wanted to chat a little!
We haven't talked like this since
the closing ceremony.
We haven't.
And yet you've gotten all
kinds of attention since.
And here I thought you
didn't like to stand out.
I don't.
Then why did you get a
perfect score in math?
That seems pretty outstanding to me.
I'm pretty sure plenty of students could
have answered problems like those.
You think so? I wonder.
Even if they could, you're in Class D.
You sure it's a good idea to acknowledge
someone with crazy high specs is in it?
I think 2-D has plenty of
remarkable students in it.
1-D does, too.
That's true, but…
The school's really
changed since last year.
Yes, I believe there
are remarkable students,
but not enough to move a
whole class, or rather,
none that give the impression they're
changing anything, like you do.
So she's gathering information in
places I can't see, is she?
I'm in a bit of a bind, myself.
I've never been dropped to Class C before,
and here I thought this
class could reach A.
And you think it should fall
to someone else to fix that?
That's a low blow.
Hey, I just had a groundbreaking idea!
You could join my class, like how
Katsuragi transferred to Class B!
That's a hell of a thing to say.
You can shoot for Class
A with us! How about it?
I can't get twenty million points
before graduation.
Besides, we don't yet know which class
will win its way to A in the end.
Y-You didn't have to take it so seriously…
Sudo's changed a lot, too.
Who changed him, hm?
Just for the record, it wasn't me.
Anyway, I'll be heading back now.
They'll be stationing me here and
there throughout the exam,
so we might meet again!
Ayanokoji.
That's twice today.
It is. What a coincidence.
How'd today go for you?
It was all I could do to get three
points from arrival bonuses.
And you?
We got eight points from arrivals, and took
first in a task for 13 points in all.
Sounds like you took off running.
We did.
Um…
No, it's nothing.
Even if Tsukishiro wants to get me expelled
by forcing me into the bottom five,
I'm in charge of my point earnings.
Which means he could manipulate
my watch or tablet,
showing me false target destinations,
but if I complained to the school,
that half-baked strategy would fail.
If he's using a White Room student,
they'd try to force me out
due to injury or illness.
Which means they'd attack
when I'm in a blind spot.
That's the most realistic
method of expelling me.
E8, huh?
Considering the travel time,
I should let this one pass.
Second twice in a row. I might have
a formidable rival on this table.
Guess I'll go back to
E6 and wait for a task.
Ayanokoji.
We meet again. Do you think we
might be on the same table?
Possibly.
Even if we head for the same areas,
our chances of meeting aren't that high.
This could just be a string
of coincidences, but…
Um, if you don't mind,
I have a favor to ask.
Such as?
If it's not an imposition, could we
stick together for a while?
Stick together? What's this about?
The truth is, last night Hosen and Amasawa
said they'd go their own ways,
so we've gotten split up.
That could be considered a strategy.
I don't believe I can reach the designated
areas very quickly on my own.
Meanwhile, I've run into you three
times since yesterday morning,
and with just one exception,
you reached the areas first.
I can't say it's wise for groups to
cooperate across school years.
If you reach a task that only has
room for one more group,
an argument is guaranteed to ensue.
I don't mind letting you take
priority for all of them.
That'll naturally result in your
point income decreasing.
This is my first deserted island exam,
so even having suitable routes
picked for me is a huge help.
Even if I did pick suitable routes,
could you keep up with me?
I'm confident in my stamina.
Or is it less that it's a bother,
and more you don't trust me?
Got it. If that's what
you want, I don't mind.
Thank you very much.
What are your plans now? We have over
an hour before the next announcement.
A quiz task appeared in F8, to the
southeast. I'm going there.
Got it. I'll come with.